我叫巴里·艾伦 我是世界上速度最快的人
My name is Barry Allen and I am the fastest man alive.
小时候 我见到
When I was a child, I saw
我母亲死于某种不可能存在的东西
my mother killed by something impossible.
跑 巴里 快跑
Run, Barry, run!
我父亲因我母亲之死而入狱
My father went to prison for her murder.
然后一次事故让我成了一个不可能的存在
Then an accident made me the impossible.
表面上 我只是一个普通的鉴证科员
To the outside world, I'm an ordinary forensic scientist,
但背地里 我运用我的速度
but secretly I use my speed
与罪恶战斗 并找出像我这样的人
to fight crime and find others like me.
总有一天 我会找到杀死我母亲的凶手
And one day, I'll find who killed my mother
为我父亲讨回公道的
and get justice for my father.
我是 闪电侠
I am... The Flash.
【闪电侠】前情提要
Previously on The Flash...
很抱歉我不相信你
I'm sorry I didn't believe you.
但在你妈妈死的那晚 你确实看到了一些东西
But you really did see something that night your mom died
你爸爸的确是无辜的
and your dad is innocent.
让你陷入昏迷的那场爆炸也杀死我的未婚夫
The explosion that put you in a coma also killed my fiance.
你能想象一下如果你能控制他的力量吗
Can you imagine if you could control his power?
如果你能驾驭它
If you could harness it,
你就可以改变它对人类的意义
you could change what it means to be human.
他叫闪电侠
He's called The Flash.
或 至少他总有一天会是
Or, at least, he will be one day.
我们必须保证他的安全
He must be kept safe.
不论你是体育课上跑的最慢的孩子
It doesn't matter if you're the slowest kid
或者是世界上跑的最快的人 都不重要
in gym class or the fastest man alive.
每个人都在奔跑
Every one of us is running.
活着就意味着奔跑
Being alive means running...
为了逃避某些事物而奔跑
running from something,
为了追逐某些事物或是
running to something
某些人而奔跑
or someone.
不论你跑的有多快
And no matter how fast you are,
总有一些东西你无法超过
there's some things you can't outrun.
总有一些东西设法追上你
Some things always manage to catch up to you.
如果是普通电影标准的话 有七、八分
Regular movie scale, that was a seven or an eight.
但是按僵尸电影标准 最高只能四分
Zombie movie scale, it was, like, a four, tops.
有僵尸电影标准这回事吗
There's a zombie movie scale?
你知道僵尸是存在于自然界之中的吗
Did you know that zombies exist in nature?
有一种特殊的菌类能感染蚂蚁
There's a species of fungi that infects ants,
让蚂蚁去攻击植物
causing the ants to attack plants
植物释放能够感染寄主的孢子
that can release spores which in turn infect new hosts.
我又成了个死书呆  对吧
I'm going full nerd again, aren't I?
-没错 -好吧
- Yep. - Yeah.
可是没关系啊
Yeah. It's okay though.
你依然是我认识的最可爱的书呆
You are still the cutest nerd that I know.
总之  我对最近的奇人异事
Anyways, I'm a lot more interested
更有兴趣
in the amazing as of late.
你是指引起"闪电"的那个东西吗
You mean 'cause of this "Streak" thing?
他是真的存在 大家都在谈论他
He's out there. People are talking about him.
你怎么知道他是个男的
How do you even know he's a he?
说不定是女的啊
Maybe it's a she.
是个男的 好吗
It's a man, okay?
你知道我都这种事情的直觉都很准的
You know I am really intuitive about this kind of stuff.
有人甚至在被从车祸中救了出来之后
Someone even posted a picture
发了一张图片
after being yanked from a car accident.
是一道红色的残影正要离开现场
It's a red blur leaving the scene.
来 你看见了什么
Here, what do you see?
我看到你男盆友来电话了
I see your boyfriend's calling.
哦 我得接这通电话
Oh, I should probably get this.
我今晚要去他那里
I'm crashing at his place tonight,
他应该在哪里给我留了钥匙
and he's supposed to leave a key for me somewhere.
嘿 宝贝 怎么了
Hey, babe. What's up?
不忙 跟巴里出来逛呢
Not much, just hanging out with Barry.
你下班了吗
You off yet?
喂
Hello.
地点在韦德大道 犯罪代码237
Code 237 on Waid Boulevard.
公然猥亵吗
Public indecency?
等等 应该是239
Wait, I think I meant a 239.
狗链松了
Dog leash violation?
有人持枪开车逃跑
Bad man with a gun in a getaway car.
快去
Go.
你没有垫子 那你有花盆吗
You don't have a mat. Do you have a planter?
他有枪 小心
He's got a gun. Look out!
他去哪里了
Where'd he go?
搞什么
What the...
钥匙在邮箱里
Key's in the mailbox.
待会见 拜
I'll see you later. Bye.
埃迪向你问好 他人真好啊
- Eddie says hi. - Nice of him.
你要吃点什么吗
You wanna grab a bite?
我快饿死了
I'm feeling a little famished.
在电影开场前我们吃了蒙古烤肉
After the Mongolian barbecue we had before the movie
还有看电影时你吃了超大号爆米花之后
and the extra large popcorn you had at the movie?
你怎么一点不胖啊
How are you not fat?
我一直有在慢跑
I've been jogging.
哦 好吧
Oh, okay.
为什么要在公众场合见面 叔叔
Why so public a meeting, uncle?
我们外出用餐是为告诉我们的敌人 我们并不害怕
We're dining out to show our enemies we're not afraid.
放松 侄子
Relax, nephew.
我们已经把窗户玻璃换成防弹的了
We've replaced the windows with bulletproof glass.
把窗户关起来
Close it up.
来
Come.
喝一杯
Have a drink.
我们的司机在偷我们的东西
Our own drivers are ripping us off.
有人花钱雇他们
Someone is paying them
来偷我们的东西
to steal from us.
除非找出他们是谁 否则你们都别想睡了
None of you will sleep until we find out who.
然后将那些窃贼
And then those thieves...
那些窃贼
Those thieves...
死定了
Will draw their last breath.
叔叔
Uncle!
闪电侠
第一季 第三集
视频字幕由 SSK字幕组 制作发布
字幕只供学习 请勿做任何商业行为
敬请关注新浪微博@SSK字幕组
合作贴吧：美剧闪电侠吧
翻译：Shooky 络睿 Jophy Rubens Espionag
-你在哪拦住他的 -我们在第八大道抓住了他
- Where'd you cut him off? - So we cut him off at eighth.
罪犯甚至一脸茫然地
I mean, the perp was in the backseat of the cruiser
坐在我们警车后座上
before he even knew what happened.
校对：Bunny Jophy
恭喜你 保尔森
Congratulations, Paulson,
昨天的逮捕行动不错
on that arrest last night.
-绝对精彩 -乔 你稍后再来吧
- Hell of a job. - You come by later, Joe.
我会教你怎么开车的
I'll give you a driving lesson, okay?
昨晚的事根本不是他的功劳 都是我干的
Wasn't even him last night. It was me.
我猜到了
I figured.
时轴：络睿  压制：hhjie  总监：Jophy
我只是没想到
I just didn't realize
你是为了荣誉而帮助他人
you were helping people for the glory.
我又不是要建一座以我名字命名的博物馆
It's not like I want a museum built in my name.
向艾瑞斯和其他人隐瞒我的能力
Keeping what I can do a secret from Iris and everyone,
比我想象中更难
it's harder than I thought.
合作贴吧：美剧闪电侠吧
我明白 但那样做比较安全
I know, but it is safer that way.
另外 我们还有活要干
Besides, me and you got work to do.
我妈妈那件案子的证据
The evidence from my mom's case.
我从储蓄库里拿出来的
I had it brought up from storage.
这个箱子我已经翻过1000遍了
I've been through this box 1,000 times.
先前 你所说的那晚发生的事
Before, your story about what really happened that night...
一道闪电划过 中间的这个男人
the lightning storm, the man in the middle of it...
我以为那是一个孩子
I thought that was a kid
在试图保护他爸爸免受牢狱之灾
trying to protect his father from prison.
但现在我知道这是真的了
But now that I know it's true,
我们要仔细检查每一个证据
we're gonna go through every scrap of evidence
直到找出对我们有用的东西
until we find something that helps us.
陪审团花了52分钟
It took the jury 52 minutes to come back
就做出了有罪判决
with a verdict of guilty.
他们动作太快了
They moved too fast,
所以我们得慢慢来
which is why we got to take our time.
巴里 乔 发生了好几起凶杀案
Barry, Joe, we got multiple homicides.
你们知道达尔比尼扬犯罪家族吗
Do you know the Darbinyan crime family?
巴里
Barry?
有发现吗
Ah. Anything?
有组织中毒性缺氧的症状
Signs of histotoxic hypoxia.
他们身体里的细胞没法吸收氧气
The cells in their bodies were unable to utilize oxygen.
暴露在有毒气体中
It's consistent with exposure to poison gas.
是什么毒
What kind of poison?
我需要做个肺泡样本
I'll need to take a lung sample,
看看能不能缩小范围
see if I can narrow it down.
另一个唯一的出口被从内部反锁了
The only other exit was bolted from the inside.
他们被困在房子里
They were trapped.
我想是有人从外面向里释放的毒气
I was thinking someone pumped gas in from the outside,
但目击者说街上空无一人
but witnesses say the street was empty.
所以毒气是从里面扩散的
So it was from the inside.
那就说明现场应该有气罐
That means there should be a canister
或是容器
or a container left behind.
气体可不会自己跑进来
The gas just didn't come in by itself.
除非毒气自己有意志
Unless it had a mind of its own.
埃迪 你能不能再调查一遍吗
Eddie, would you mind canvassing again?
肯定有人看到了可疑现象
Somebody had to have seen something suspicious.
好了 解释一下
Okay, explain.
老大倒在桌子旁
The boss collapsed by the table.
这个人却离他有十英尺远
This guy made it 10 feet away.
那个人还有能移动
That guy had a chance to move off
并且朝窗户开了三枪
and fire three shots into the window
试图打破玻璃
trying to break the glass.
他们本来都在同一个点的
But they all started in the same spot,
这意味着他们理应同时被毒气感染
which means they should have all been affected by the gas
但是恰恰相反 就好像
at the same time, but instead, it's as if...
他们是逐个被袭击的
They were attacked one by one.
直觉告诉我 如果我们要破这个案子
My gut feeling, if we're gonna solve this one,
你我都需要
you and me are gonna need...
-后援 -没错
- Backup. - Yeah.
太棒了 一个能操纵毒气的超能力者
Fascinating, a meta-human that can manipulate poison gas.
就只有毒气吗
Is it just poisonous gas,
还是他能控制所有气体
or can he control all aerated substances?
他是怎么和气体产生联合的
And how is he able to formulate the connection?
是通过生理机能还是通过心理念力
Is it physiological or psychological?
这超能人可以通过气态物质
This individual can create
形成一种精神联结
a mental nexus using gaseous substances.
你是说在分子层面上和气体交流吗
You mean connect with gases on a molecular level?
-是的 -那酷毙了
- Yes. - That is ridiculously cool.
他们对这种事情相当激动
They get really excited about this stuff.
唯一能让我感到激动的是
The only thing I'm excited about
把罪犯缉拿归案
is putting criminals behind bars.
但是铁高监狱根本
Except Iron Heights isn't exactly equipped
关不住超能力者
to handle meta-humans.
那么我想 幸运的是到目前为止
Then I guess it's fortunate the ones
你所遇到的超能力者都已经不在了
you've encountered so far are no longer with us.
除非我们打算将遇到的所有
Well, unless we're planning on executing
超级罪犯都就地处决
every super criminal we stop,
否则你们这群天才就要想想
you geniuses are gonna have to come up
要把他们关在哪里了
with someplace else to hold them.
超能力者监狱 美腻死了
A meta-human prison. Sweet.
除非我们找到除去他们能力的方法
Until we figure a way to remove their powers.
这儿有个地方或许能关得住他们
There is one place here that might hold them.
你在开玩笑吧
You can't be serious.
我们很久没有下去过了
I mean, we haven't been down there since...
那已经被封了
it's cordoned off.
思科说的对
Cisco is right.
那能被改造成
It could be modified to act
个临时监狱
as a makeshift prison.
什么地方
What could?
粒子加速器
The particle accelerator.
未来从今晚开始
Tonight, the future begins.
我和我的团队在这里所做的工作
The work my team and I will do here
将改变我们对物理学的理解
will change our understanding of physics,
将带来能源上进一步的发展
will bring about advancements in power,
和医学上的进步
advancements in medicine.
相信我 未来将比你
And trust me, that future
想象中发展得更快
will be here faster than you think.
韦尔斯博士 我们刚刚得到最新的气象报告
Dr. Wells, we just got the latest weather report.
一个巨大的雷暴正滚滚而来
A big thunderstorm is rolling in.
我们并不是要发射宇宙飞船
We're not launching a space shuttle.
会没问题的
We'll be fine.
去大溪地吗
Tahiti?
我知道途程很长 罗尼
I know it's a long flight, Ronnie,
但我们可以看电视剧《女子监狱》来找乐子
but we can binge watch Orange Is The New Black.
哦 好的
Oh, okay.
但是意大利怎么样呢
But what about Italy?
披萨和葡萄酒以及更多的披萨
Pizza and wine and more pizza.
是的 但是意大利没有迈泰鸡尾酒
Yes, but Italy doesn't have mai tais,
没有迈泰鸡尾酒的蜜月
and a honeymoon isn't a honeymoon
就不是蜜月了
without nai tais.
韦尔斯博士 加速器已经准备好了
Dr. Wells, the accelerator is primed
可以进行粒子注射了
and ready for particle injection.
好的 我觉得我应该说点意义重大的话
Well, I feel I should say something profound
像是 人类迈出一小步 什么的
like "one small step for man,"
但是我所能想到的就是
but all I can think of to say is,
我等这一天的到来已经等了好几个世纪
I feel like I've waited for this day for centuries.
就这样吗
That's it?
你可能以为将会有一声巨响
You'd think there'd be, like, a loud bang.
如果有一声巨响 那我们就有大麻烦了
If there was a loud bang, we'd all be in big trouble.
相信建立系统的人吧
Take it from the guy who helped build it.
女士们先生们 我们成了
Ladies and gentlemen, we did it.
那就选迈泰吧
Mai tais it is.
那是
Was that...
一声巨响
A loud bang.
凯特琳
Caitlin.
你听见我的话了吗
Did you hear me?
我们要下去看加速器
We're going down to the accelerator ring.
事实上 韦尔斯博士  我可以让凯特琳帮助我
Actually, Dr. Wells, I could use Caitlin's help
来确认毒气的种类
identifying the poison gas.
好的
Okay.
你觉得这样可以吗
If that's okay with you?
我们走吧
Let's go.
欢迎来到中城警局
Welcome to the CCPD.
这就是你的白天的工作咯
So this is your day job.
嗯哼
Mm-hmm.
我要挖出你的心
I'm gonna rip out your hearts
当午餐吃
and eat 'em for lunch.
真是令人高兴
Delightful.
小白鼠 我要尽快拿到枪上的指纹
Lab rat, I need prints off this gun pronto.
艾伦
Allen!
奥尔洛夫案件的纤维分析他妈的跑哪去了
Where the hell is the fiber analysis on the Orloff case?
在楼上 已经全部完成了
Upstairs. It's all finished.
我可以跑上去拿下了
I can just run up and bring it down.
你去拿 估计得要三天才能拿到
With you, that could be three days from now.
我和你一起去 你是谁
I'll go with you. Who are you?
凯特琳 斯诺博士
Dr. Caitlin Snow,
巴里的私人医生
Barry's personal physician.
这是您要的奥尔洛夫f案件的
The fiber analysis for the Orloff case,
纤维分析
like you asked for,
长官
sir.
收拾一下你的实验室
Clean up your lab.
乱七八糟的
It's a mess.
闪电当时就在房子里
The lightning was in the house.
我让我的儿子快跑
I told my son to run,
但他消失了
he disappeared,
然后我看到了血迹
and that's when I saw the blood.
你的指纹就在凶器上
Your prints were on the murder weapon.
我当时是要稳住那把刀
I needed to stabilize the knife.
我是个医生
I'm a doctor.
我是想要救她
I was trying to save her.
我没杀我的妻子
I didn't kill my wife.
乔 你告诉他们
Joe, tell them.
你懂我的 我们的孩子是朋友
You know me. Our kids are friends.
你告诉他们啊 乔
You tell them, Joe.
难道我还会想知道你在看什么吗
Do I even want to know what you were looking at?
仅仅是工作
It's just work.
一些没有正确归档的旧案子
Some old cases weren't filed properly.
警探 你在这儿干嘛呢
Detective. What are you doing here?
乔 我以为你还在验尸房呢
Joe, I thought you were at the morgue.
我决定把工作带回家做
I decided to bring some work home.
你来着干什么
Why are you here?
嗯 我正在找你
Yes, well, I've been looking for you.
我想也许我们能回到犯罪现场
I thought maybe we could go back to the crime scene,
再仔细检查下 看看我们有没有遗漏什么
re-canvass, see if we missed anything.
工作为先 对吧
Always work the case, right?
是你教我的
That's what you taught me.
喔 你有在听啊
Wow, you've been listening.
好的 我们走吧
Okay, let's hit it.
你介意我用一下你家的洗手间吗
You mind if I use your bathroom?
右边的第一扇门就是了
It's the first door on the right.
我去车里等你
I'll be in the car.
再见 宝贝
Bye, baby.
再见 爸爸
Bye, dad.
好了 不能再这样子了
Okay, this has got to stop.
我来这儿本想给我女朋友一个惊喜
I came here to surprise my girlfriend,
但现在我却要和她的爸爸一起去犯罪现场
and now I'm going to a crime scene with her dad...
这可不是我下午的计划
not exactly the afternoon I was planning on.
我知道 我知道 只是
I know, I know, it's just...
现在还不是告诉他的合适时机
it's not the right time to tell him.
那什么时候是呢 艾瑞斯
When is, Iris?
我了解我的爸爸 他会杀了我们
I know my dad. He'll kill us.
现在 你正在扼杀我们
Right now, you're killing us.
管子里的铜排列成一个空腔
The copper in the tube is arranged to form cavities,
我们能用那些空腔作为储藏单元
and we can use those cavities as containment cells.
当然 我们还需要设计它们来
Of course, we'll have to design them to counteract
抑制超能力者的能力 不过
meta-human abilities, but...
也许刚好能行
might just work.
首先 我们要减弱龙门架上
First, we have to decouple the main injection system
主要注入系统的震波
on the gantry level.
我去去就来
I'll be right back.
为什么不让我来呢
Why don't I do that?
我需要锻炼
I need the exercise.
核心控制室有异常
There's an anomaly in the core chamber.
加速器环结构的整体性正在恢复
The ring's structural integrity is holding.
已经开始了链式反应
It's started a chain reaction.
这个体统就要崩溃了 我们必须关闭它
The system is collapsing. We need to shut it down.
我们在这儿关闭不了加速器
We can't ramp down the accelerator from here.
- 我们只能手动操作了 -快去
- We need to do it manually. - Go.
- 我也去 - 罗尼 不要
- I'll come with. - Ronnie, no.
我是首席工程师
I'm the lead engineer.
我知道怎么操纵关闭阀门
I know how to operate the shutdown valve.
-那不安全 -凯特 我必须去
- It's not safe. - Cait, I have to go.
好吧 你呆在这儿
Okay, you stay here.
在爆炸前我们只有几分钟了
We've only got a few minutes before this thing blows,
如果我没有及时回来 你就要开始关闭系统了
and if I'm not back in time, you need to initiate lockdown.
没门 我不会关闭这扇门的
No way. I am not closing this door.
我没法再打开它
I won't be able to open it again.
思科 如果你不封闭住爆炸波
Cisco, if you don't seal off the blast,
这栋建筑里的所有人都得死
everyone in this building will die,
包括凯特琳在内
including Caitlin.
好吧 答应我
Okay, now promise me.
设置好你的表
Set your watch.
2分钟倒计时
Two minutes.
你一定要回来
You're coming back.
思科
Cisco.
思科 我们该走了
Cisco, we're ready to go.
再回到这里来 一定很难过吧
Must be hard, coming back down here.
那晚发生太多事前了
A lot happened that night.
如果你觉得需要谈谈
If you feel the need to talk...
我只想着
I was just thinking,
我们必须搞定那些电压计算
we need to nail those voltage calculations.
只要有一个错误 氦气就会反冲爆炸
One fault, and the helium blowback
就能毁了这些装置
could damage the mountings.
聪明
Smart.
我能问你一些事吗
Can I ask you something
你不一定要回答
that you don't have to answer?
我最不喜欢这类问题
My least favorite kind of question.
问吧
Shoot.
罗尼 他以前是个什么样的人
Ronnie. What was he like?
你几乎从不谈起他
You just never talk about him that much.
我们在粒子加速器上工作时相遇的
We met when we were working on the particle accelerator.
他是结构工程师
He was the structural engineer.
他总是开玩笑说他基本上就是一个
He liked to joke that he was basically
高价的水管工
a very high-priced plumber.
我们非常不同
We were very different.
你也许已经注意到了我有点
You might have noticed I can be a bit...
谨慎
Guarded.
罗尼知道怎么逗我开心
Ronnie knew how to make me laugh.
他曾经说我们像火与冰
He used to say we were like fire and ice.
那天晚上他本来不应该在那儿的
He wasn't supposed to be there that night.
他在那儿仅仅是为了我
He was just there for me.
如果他没有
If he hadn't...
结果显示这个组织里没有气体残余了
This says that there was no residue of gas in the tissue,
毒气或者别的什么
poisonous or otherwise.
肯定已经蒸发完了
It must have evaporated.
我们需要一个新鲜的样品
We'll need to get a fresh sample.
等等 这个不对
Wait, this can't be right.
这里显示在这个组织里有
This says that there are two distinct strands of DNA
两条不同的DNA链
inside the tissue.
其他人的DNA怎么会进入死者的肺部呢
How did someone else's DNA get inside the victim's lungs?
嗯 我的事情都办完了 所以我在购物中心停了会
Well, my docket was clear, so I stopped by the mall
给你买了返校节上穿的衣服
to pick up your homecoming dress.
我真是个好妈妈
I am a great mom.
晚餐见 甜心
I'll see you for dinner, sweetie.
数据库中没有与这个匹配的DNA
There's no DNA match in the database.
我不明白
I don't understand.
为什么一次化学攻击
Why would a chemical attack
会将另一个人的DNA留在死者的体内呢
leave behind another person's DNA inside the victim?
如果我们寻找的超能力者
What if the meta-human we're looking for
并不是控制气体呢
doesn't control gas?
如果他是变成气体呢
What if he becomes it?
霍德华法官
Judge Howard.
很高兴再次见到你
It's nice to see you again.
你死了啊
You died.
你说得那好像是场意外一样
You say that like it was an accident.
你记得在法庭上你跟我说的
You remember the last thing you said to me
最后一件事吗
in the courtroom?
愿上帝保佑你的灵魂
May God have mercy on your soul.
各单位注意 我们接到一个
All available units, we have a report
毒气袭击案的报告
of a toxic gas attack
就在中城购物中心
in the central city shopping mall.
巴里 别去
Barry, don't.
我们还不太了解我们面对的是什么
We don't know enough about what we're facing yet.
这样不安全
It's not safe.
凯特琳 我必须去
Caitlin, I have to go.
我进入了购物中心的安保系统
I patched into the mall's security system.
根据目击者的说法 毒气袭击
According to witnesses, the gas attack
发生在北翼楼的主电梯里
was in the main elevator in the north wing.
哪一个是北翼楼
Which one is the north wing?
有贝利大汉堡店的那个
The one with The Big Belly Burger.
我也要吃饭
I eat.
退后 请大家退后
Back up. Please, keep back.
你为什么杀了那个女人
Why did you kill that woman?
因为她该死
She deserved to die.
你赶紧滚吧
Now go run away.
我还有一个人要杀
I still have one more name on my list.
别逼我把你也杀了
Don't make me add you to it.
巴里
Barry.
巴里 能听到我说话吗
Barry, can you hear me?
他的生命特征很微弱 但是他还活着 韦尔斯博士
His vitals are weak, but he's alive, Dr. Wells.
我肯定他没事
I'm sure he's fine.
我呼吸不了
I can't breathe.
他需要氧气 快去准备急救
He needs oxygen. Get the crash cart!
巴里
- - Barry!
巴里 快点把我气管切开
- Barry. - Cut me open.
毒气仍然在我身体里 他给我们带来了样本
The poison's still in me. He brought us a sample.
凯特琳 我们得做肺部活体组织检查
Caitlin, we need to do a pulmonary biopsy,
提取那个气体的活性组织
extract an active portion of that gas.
我不能给你打麻醉药
I can't give you any anesthetic.
你的代谢功能会把麻药药性迅速的挥发掉
Your metabolism will burn right through it.
我恢复得很快 记得吗
I heal quick, remember?
开始吧
Do it.
思科 把注射器给我
Cisco, give me the syringe.
会很疼
This is gonna hurt a lot.
只是个很小的针 你可能感觉不到
It's a small needle. You probably won't even feel it.
你肯定会感觉得到的
You're definitely going to feel it.
他醒了
The Streak lives.
要不是你的肺部细胞再生得那么快
You'd be dead if your lung cells
你就死了
didn't regenerate so quickly.
我的胸口感觉就像
My chest feels like that one time
抽第一根烟的感觉
I had a cigarette.
我知道 吸烟有害健康
Yeah, teen me lived for danger.
这不好笑 你可能会
This isn't funny. You could've...
但我没有
I didn't.
现在我们有样本了 我们得开始着手分析了
Now that we have a sample, we'll get to work analyzing it,
弄清楚到底毒气的成分是什么
figure out the makeup of the poison,
也许能得到他身份的线索
maybe get a clue as to his human identity.
或者至少找到方法让他没法再变成绿雾
Or at least a way to stop him from turning into a mist.
绿雾怪 恩 这就是他的名字
The Mist. Okay, that's his name.
不用再讨论了
End of discussion.
我得去警局
I have to get to the station.
你需要休息
You should be resting.
我得和乔谈谈
I have to talk to Joe.
乔 我发现他了
Joe. I had him.
那个超能力者 我们一直弄错了
The meta-human. We were wrong.
他不是能控制在空气中传播的毒素
He's not controlling airborne toxins.
他是自己能变成毒气
He can literally transform himself into poison gas.
第一次听说
That's new.
受害人是一个法官
The victim was a judge.
我们在调查她以前的案子
We're going through some of her old cases
看看能否找到联系
to see if there's a connection.
太晚了
It's too late.
我应该再快一点的
I should have been faster.
把心放在工作上
Focus on the job.
现在别想那些
Don't think about that right now.
你不会想知道我在想什么的
You don't want to know what I'm thinking about.
我父亲在狭窄的牢房里
My dad has spent 14 years
呆了14年 来赎那个他根本没有犯过的罪
in a 6x8-foot cell for a crime he didn't commit.
我救不了我妈妈 但是我可以救他
I couldn't save my mom, but I can save him.
我不是答应过你
Didn't I promise you
我们会一起想办法把你父亲救出来吗
that we would get your father out of prison together?
我不需要你的帮助 乔
I don't need your help, Joe.
我一个人就可以把他带出来
I could be in and out of there with him
没人能够发现我
before anyone even sees me.
好啊
Okay.
你带他越狱出来了
You break him out of there.
然后呢
Then what?
他一生都会在逃亡中度过
He's on the run for the rest of his life.
而且我想他也没你跑得那么快
And something tell me he's not as fast as you are.
你根本不知道那是种什么感觉
You don't know what it's like there.
你觉得我不能理解
You think I don't understand
你的感受吗
what you're feeling?
我当警察的年限
I have been a cop for almost as long
跟你的年龄差不多了
as you've been alive.
所以你应该知道 穿上你那身衣服
So you should know, putting on that suit
不代表能保证所有人都安全
does not make everybody safe.
你救了那么多人
For every person you save,
总有一个人你是救不了的
there's gonna be somebody you can't.
你所要面对的最困难的事
And the hardest thing you're gonna have to face
不是那些有着特异功能的怪物们
is not some monster out there with powers.
而是当你什么事都不能做的时候
It's gonna be that feeling of uselessness
的那种无奈与挫败感
when you can't do anything.
或者是当你犯了错时压迫着你的愧疚感
Or the guilt that weighs on you when you make a mistake.
有些事 巴里 你无法与之斗争
Some things, Barry, you can't fight.
有些事 你只能学着接受它
Some things you just have to live with.
是的 我记录下来了
Yes, I'm writing this down.
在受到那团气体攻击的时候
Red streak at the mall
你看到了红色的闪电
during the gas attack.
感谢你的来电
Thank you for calling.
一直这样
Never fails.
线索费总是能吸引一些吸毒者和疯子
Tip lines bring out the potheads and the crazies.
他们看清楚那道闪电的脸了吗
Did they get a good look at the Streak's face?
你该不会也这样吧
Not you too.
你在这儿干什么
What are you doing here anyway?
我们得谈谈
We need to talk.
我想了一下你说的话
I thought about what you said, and...
我知道你要说什么
I know what you're gonna say.
我懂
I understand.
我是爸爸的同事
I'm your dad's partner.
不 你不明白
No, no, no, you don't understand.
我从来没有交过一个认真的男友
I have never really had a serious boyfriend.
周旋在我爸爸和巴里和工作之间
Between dad and Barry and work,
我的生活一直被填得满满的
my life has been full.
我真的很喜欢你
And I really like you,
然后我想如果我跟我父亲说了我们俩的事
but I thought that if I told my dad about us,
这一切都变得真实起来
then it would make this real,
突然得 我就多了一样 我可能失去或者是
and suddenly, it's something that I could lose
搞砸的东西了
or screw up.
我真希望会变成真的
I wanted it to be real.
埃迪
Eddie.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我并不是想要吓你 然后就那么离开
I didn't mean to scare you, leaving like that.
没关系 我懂的
It's okay. I get it.
你必须得走
You had to go.
只是
It's just...
那是那晚罗尼跟我说的最后一件事了
that's the last thing that Ronnie said to me that night.
我妈妈14年前去世了
My mother died 14 years ago.
我曾经以为我越不去想这件事
I used to think that the further away I got from it,
我就越不会觉得伤心
the less it would hurt.
但是有一天 疼痛却
But some days, the pain,
远比事发当天来的还要猛烈
it's worse than the day that it happened.
有些事你无法反抗
Some things you can't fight.
很长一段时间以来
For so long,
我都不敢进那个洞里
I've been terrified of going into that hole.
我跟你一起去呢
What if I went with you?
罗尼在哪 思科 他在哪
Where's Ronnie? Cisco, where is he?
-他还在里面 -什么 把门打开
- He's still inside. - What? Open the door.
我不能 我们进入了封锁模式
I can't. We're in lockdown mode.
思科 我们必须让他出来 不然他会死的
Cisco, we have to get him out of there or he'll die.
-思科 你听到没 -罗尼 是我
- Cisco, can you hear me? - Ronnie, it's me.
凯特琳
Caitlin.
思科在那吗
Is Cisco there?
是的 罗尼 我在 我听着
Yeah, Ronnie, I'm here. I'm listening.
我调正了磁力 改变了射线方向
I adjusted the magnets to redirect the beam
看看能不能让系统减压
to try and vent the system
所以爆炸会往上扩散而不是向外冲击
so the blast goes up and not out.
我需要重置离子的物理参数
I'll need to reset the particle parameters
来抵消
to compensate.
思科去做了
Cisco's doing it.
一定还有别的出路
There has to be another way out of there.
你找找看
You have to find it.
凯特 这连锁反应
Cait, the chain reaction,
我没办法挽回
I can't reverse it.
为了保护你的安全 门必须封锁起来
The doors need to stay shut to protect you.
你还在吗
You still there?
我在
I'm here.
凯特琳 不管发生了什么
Caitlin, whatever happens...
罗尼
Ronnie.
Ronnie!
那天他拯救了那么多生命
He saved so many lives that day,
但是却没有人知道他做了什么
and no one will ever know what he did.
我知道
I do.
他是个英雄
He was a hero.
我不想他成为英雄
I didn't want him to be a hero.
我只想他成为我的丈夫
I wanted him to be my husband.
巴里 凯特琳 你们在下面吗
Barry, Caitlin, you down there?
你们应该来看看这个
You got to come look at this.
嘿 快看这个
Hey, check this out.
这是我们从你的肺里收集的
It's a 3D molecular model of the gas
气体的3D分子模型
we retrieved from your lungs.
我们已经鉴别出了毒素
We have identified the toxin.
氢氰酸吗
Hydrogen cyanide?
有意思的是氰化物里
What's interesting is what's mixed in
的混合物 一种镇定剂
with the cyanide... A sedative.
没错
Of course.
爆炸那晚 查查是否有人被处决
The night of the explosion, find out if anyone was executed.
为什么
Why?
那个镇定剂是在死刑犯
That sedative is given to criminals on death row
进入氰化氢毒气室之前
before they go to the gas chamber
给他们注射的
and breathe in hydrogen cyanide.
就是那样
That's right.
的确有人被处决
There was someone executed.
-凯尔·尼木布斯 -就是他
- Kyle Nimbus. - That's him.
他是达尔比尼扬犯罪家族的重用之人
He was a hit man for the Darbinyan crime family.
他们背叛了他并且出庭作证
They turned on him and testified.
特里萨·霍华德 是审判他的法官
Judge Theresa Howard was the judge at his trial.
她判决了他死刑
She sentenced him to death.
他当他正中毒气时
He must have been affected
肯定受到了爆炸的影响
by the explosion while he was being gassed.
记录显示死刑执行完成
Records indicate the execution was completed.
那就是为什么匹配不到他的原因
That's why there wasn't a match.
DNA数据库只记录了活着的人
The DNA database only has records of the living.
没错
Right.
他说他还有一个人要去杀
He said there was one more person on his list.
查查逮捕记录 谁抓的他
Check the arrest record. Who caught him?
那可能是他的下一个袭击目标
That could be his next attack.
巴里 是探长
Barry, the lead detective...
我是来看亨利·艾伦
Here to see Henry Allen.
在这签名
Sign here.
个人私物放这
Personal effects here.
铁山监狱
-埃迪 -巴里 怎么了
- Eddie. - Barry, what's up?
嗨 你知道乔去哪了吗
Hey, do you know where Joe went?
他没有带电话
He's not picking up his cell.
额 我不知道
Uh, not sure.
埃迪 我有很重要的事要和他说
Eddie, it's really important I speak to him.
我需要知道他去哪了
I need to know where he went.
他去铁高监狱看你的父亲了
He went to Iron Heights to see your dad.
巴里
Barry.
我逆向制造出了毒素的解毒剂
I reverse-engineered an antidote to the toxin.
我希望你不会用到它
I hope you won't need it.
-你来这做什么 -巴里还好吗
What are you doing here? Is Barry all right?
他很好
He's fine.
那是什么风把你吹来了
Then to what do I owe this visit?
我知道我早就应该来看你了
I know I should have come to see you sooner.
你来这不是就为了和一个
You just weren't up for a little chitchat
在他儿子面前杀死自己妻子的男人聊天吧
with a man who murdered his wife in front of his own son?
我知道你没有杀死你的妻子
Except now I know you didn't kill your wife.
巴里 我调出了铁高监狱的详图
Barry, I pulled up the specs on Iron Heights Prison.
那里戒备森严
It's maximum security,
但我想我可以给你讲讲怎么闯进去那里
but I think I can talk you through breaking in there.
不用麻烦了
Don't bother.
从我11岁开始
I've been figuring out
我就在想办法
how to break into that place
闯进那个地方
since I was 11.
一些新证据已经出现
Some new evidence has come to light.
但我不能细说
I can't go into detail.
只是
It's just...
听我说 重要的是
Look, the important thing is,
我要重新调查这个案件
I'm reopening the case.
我要找到谁是杀死诺拉的真正凶手
I'm gonna find out who really killed Nora,
我向你保证 亨利
and I promise you, Henry,
我会把你救出去
I'm going to get you out of here.
对不起
I am so sorry.
你不相信我没关系
It doesn't matter that you didn't believe in me...
因为你总是相信我儿子
Because you always believed in my son.
尼木布斯
Nimbus.
-你应该早死了 -彼此彼此
- You're supposed to be dead. - Same to you.
乔
Joe?
Joe!
救命
Help!
守卫
Guards!
快来人啊
Somebody help!
快抓到他
Go get him.
你是来完成毒气室未完成的事吗
So you've come to finish what the gas chamber couldn't?
你得去一个你不能伤害任何人的地方呆着
You're going somewhere you can't hurt anyone ever again.
你错了
Wrong.
他在乔身上用了解毒剂
He used the antidote on Joe.
你要离他远点 巴里
You need to stay away from him, Barry.
不要吸入他的气体
Do not breathe him in.
我不确定那有用 伙计
I'm not sure how that helps me, guys.
你不能直接和他打 巴里
You can't fight him, Barry.
就让他一直攻击你
Just keep him coming at you.
那会消耗他的体力
That should sap his strength.
毒气是最不稳定的物质
Gas is the least stable form of matter.
这个超能力者不能长时间
This meta-human will not be able
保持他的烟雾形态
to stay in his mist form for long.
他的粒子需要重新组合
His particles will need to reform.
巴里
Barry.
我们赢了
We win.
我看你睡着有一会儿了
It's been a while since I watched you sleep.
救你可真让人筋疲力尽啊
Rescuing you is exhausting.
我真的怀念以前能够
I really miss the ability
罚你不准出门的能力
to be able to ground you.
抱歉我就这样长大了
Sorry I went and grew up.
我今晚本来能够把我爸爸从监狱里救出来
I could have got my dad out of Iron Heights tonight.
我知道
I know.
但你是对的
But you were right.
不该用那种方式
That's not the way.
- 爸爸 - 哦
- Daddy. - Oh.
宝贝 我很好 别担心
Baby, I'm fine. Don't worry.
你们好好聊聊吧
I'll let you guys talk.
搭档
Partner.
你们两个同时到的吗
You two arrive at the same time?
爸爸 我们有些事需要告诉你
Dad, we have something that we need to tell you.
爸爸 我想说的是
Dad, the thing is...
你们正在交往
you two are dating.
- 我知道 - 你怎么知道的
- I know. - You do?
我是一名侦探 记得吗
I'm a detective, remember?
而且你们两个都太不会撒谎了
And both of you are lousy liars.
你不生气吗
So you're not mad?
哦 我很生气
Oh, I'm mad.
要不是医生没收了我的枪
And if the doctor hadn't confiscated my gun,
我们的谈话将会完全不一样
we'd be having an entirely different conversation.
好吧 我该让你们单独聊聊
Well, I should let you two talk,
我还是出去吧
and I'll just be outside
顺便研究一下证人保护计划
looking into the witness protection program.
对不起
I'm sorry.
艾瑞斯 这件事会变得复杂
Iris, this is going to be complicated.
你知道我不喜欢复杂的东西
You know I don't like complicated.
你喜欢他吗
Do you like him?
是的 我喜欢他
Yeah, I do.
我会尽我最大的努力不杀了他
Then I will do my damnedest not to shoot him.
这是我唯一的要求了
That is all I ask.
能控制住吗
Will it hold?
这个屏障是由
The barrier is powered by
一个8.3特斯拉的超导电磁铁驱动的
an 8.3 Tesla superconducting electromagnet,
这大约是100000倍的
which is about 100,000 times the strength
地球磁场强度
of earth's magnetic field.
换句话说 能
In other words, yes.
嗯 他生气了
Hmm. He's mad.
好吧 晚安
Well, good night.
所以我们应该开始习惯于
So we're just supposed to get used to
在关着邪恶的超能力者的
working above a makeshift prison
临时监狱工作吗
housing evil people with superpowers.
你会惊讶地发现你能习惯的 凯特琳
You'd be surprised what you can get used to, Caitlin.
凯特琳
Caitlin.
我能和你说几句话吗
Could I talk to you for a second?
当然 怎么啦
Sure. What's up?
关于罗尼死的那天晚上
It's about the night that Ronnie died.
我
I...
思科 我没事
look, Cisco, I'm okay.
我以为来到这里能够解放下自己
I thought coming down here would undo me,
但想起罗尼为了保护我们所做的事
but thinking about what Ronnie did to protect us...
那让我更加爱他
It just made me love him more.
来吧
Come on.
我需要冰激凌或者酒
I need ice cream or a drink.
看看谁先喝醉吧
Let's see which one we hit first.
乔会没事的
Joe's gonna be okay.
你知道吗 最近我一直在想妈妈
You know, lately I've been thinking about mom.
非常想
A lot.
我想她
I miss her.
我跟你讲过你学走路那时的事吗
Did I ever tell you about the time you learned to walk?
讲过几次
A couple times.
其他人都比你早学会走路
Everyone was walking before you.
每个小朋友都在社区里奔跑
All the little babies running around the neighborhood,
你却没有
not you.
但是你的妈妈一点都不担心
But your mom was never worried.
她只是说 当你要去某个地方的时候
She just said, e'll walk
你一定会走路的
when he has someplace to go.
不出所料 第一次你能走几步的时候
and sure enough, the first time you took a few steps,
你走得非常快 你不仅仅是走
you moved so quick, you didn't just walk,
你开始
you started...
奔跑
To run.
你跑向了你的妈妈 巴里
And you ran to your mom, Barry.
扑进了她的怀里
Right into her arms.
你有； 要去的地方
You had someplace to go.
我以为成为世上最快的人
I thought being the fastest man alive
会使我的生活轻松些
would make my life easier...
以为我能够逃离任何事
that I could outrun anything.
结果发现 没有人能够逃离痛苦
Turns out, no one can outrun pain.
来人啊救命 来人啊
Somebody help! Please, somebody!
生活是可悲的
Life is tragic.
但它也是珍贵的
But it's also precious...
甜蜜的
And sweet...
踪迹最新动态
不同寻常的
And extraordinary.
我知道纪念我妈妈的生命的唯一方式
And the only way I know to honor my mom's life
就是继续奔跑
is to keep running.
韦尔斯博士
Dr. Wells.
韦尔斯博士 罗尼做到了
Dr. Wells, Ronnie did it.
他减压了系统
He vented the system.
科技之星实验室应该能坚持住了
S.T.A.R. Labs should hold.
好样的
Good man.
我现在下去
I'm on my way down.
很快就能见面了 巴里
See you soon, Barry.